{
    "exam_name": "C Programming Set 3",
    "total_marks": 20,
    "time_limit": 20,
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    int x = 5;<br>    printf(\"%d\", x++);<br>    printf(\"%d\", x);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "55",
                "B": "56",
                "C": "65",
                "D": "66"
            },
            "correct_answer": "B"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    int a = 10;<br>    int b = 20;<br>    int c;<br>    c = a++ + b;<br>    printf(\"%d\", c);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "30",
                "B": "31",
                "C": "40",
                "D": "41"
            },
            "correct_answer": "A"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    int i = 0;<br>    while (i < 5) {<br>        printf(\"%d \", i);<br>        i++;<br>    }<br>    printf(\"%d\", i);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "0 1 2 3 4",
                "B": "0 1 2 3 4 5",
                "C": "0 1 2 3",
                "D": "Infinite loop"
            },
            "correct_answer": "B"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>int main() {<br>    int a = 2;<br>    if (a >> 1)<br>        printf(\"%d\\n\", a);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "0",
                "b": "1",
                "c": "2",
                "d": "No Output"
            },
            "correct_answer": "c"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    int x = 5;<br>    x = x << 2;<br>    printf(\"%d\", x);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "5",
                "B": "20",
                "C": "10",
                "D": "8"
            },
            "correct_answer": "B"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    int x = 4, y, z;<br>    y = --x;<br>    z = x--;<br>    printf(\"%d%d%d\", x, y, z);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "3 2 3",
                "b": "2 2 3",
                "c": "3 2 2",
                "d": "2 3 3"
            },
            "correct_answer": "d"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    int x = 4;<br>    int *p = &x;<br>    int *k = p++;<br>    int r = p - k;<br>    printf(\"%d\", r);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "4",
                "b": "8",
                "c": "1",
                "d": "Run time error"
            },
            "correct_answer": "c"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    int a = 5, b = -7, c = 0, d;<br>    d = ++a && ++b || ++c;<br>    printf(\"\\n%d%d%d%d\", a, b, c, d);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "6 -6 0 0",
                "b": "6 -5 0 1",
                "c": "-6 -6 0 1",
                "d": "6 -6 0 1"
            },
            "correct_answer": "d"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    int b = 6;<br>    int c = 7;<br>    int a = ++b + c--;<br>    printf(\"%d\", a);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "Run time error",
                "b": "15",
                "c": "13",
                "d": "14"
            },
            "correct_answer": "d"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    double b = 8;<br>    b++;<br>    printf(\"%lf\", b);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "9.000000",
                "b": "9",
                "c": "9.0",
                "d": "Run time error"
            },
            "correct_answer": "a"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    int k = 0;<br>    double b = k++ + ++k + k--;<br>    printf(\"%d\", k);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "6",
                "b": "1",
                "c": "5",
                "d": "undefined"
            },
            "correct_answer": "b"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    int h = 8;<br>    int b = h++ + h++ + h++;<br>    printf(\"%d\\n\", h);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "9",
                "b": "10",
                "c": "12",
                "d": "11"
            },
            "correct_answer": "d"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>int main() {<br>    int a = -1, b = 4, c = 1, d;<br>    d = ++a && ++b || ++c;<br>    printf(\"%d, %d, %d, %d\\n\", a, b, c, d);<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "0, 4, 2, 1",
                "b": "0, 5, 2, 1",
                "c": "-1, 4, 1, 1",
                "d": "0, 5, 1, 0"
            },
            "correct_answer": "a"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    int i;<br>    for (i = 0; i < 5; i++) {<br>        if (i % 2 == 0)<br>            continue;<br>        printf(\"%d \", i);<br>    }<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "0 1 2 3 4",
                "B": "1 3",
                "C": "0 2 4",
                "D": "Compilation Error"
            },
            "correct_answer": "B"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>double k = 0;<br>for (k = 0.0; k < 3.0; k++);<br>printf(\"%lf\", k);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "2.000000",
                "b": "4.000000",
                "c": "3.000000",
                "d": "Run time error"
            },
            "correct_answer": "c"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>int i = 0;<br>do<br>{<br>    i++;<br>    if (i == 2)<br>        continue;<br>    printf(\"In while loop \");<br>} while (i < 2);<br>printf(\"%d\\n\", i);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "In while loop 2",
                "b": "In while loop in while loop 3",
                "c": "In while loop 3",
                "d": "Infinite loop"
            },
            "correct_answer": "a"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    int i = 0;<br>    for (; i < 5; i++) {<br>        printf(\"%d \", i);<br>}<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "0 1 2 3 4",
                "B": "1 2 3 4 5",
                "C": "0 1 2 3",
                "D": "Infinite loop"
            },
            "correct_answer": "A"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    int x = 5;<br>    x = x + 2 * 3;<br>    printf(\"%d\", x);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "11",
                "B": "15",
                "C": "13",
                "D": "Compilation Error"
            },
            "correct_answer": "A"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>    int x = 5;<br>    int *ptr = &x;<br>    printf(\"%p\", ptr);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "5",
                "B": "Address of x in hexadecimal format",
                "C": "0",
                "D": "Compilation Error"
            },
            "correct_answer": "B"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>void foo();<br>printf(\"1 \");<br>foo();<br>void foo() {<br>    printf(\"2 \");<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "1 2",
                "b": "Compile time error",
                "c": "1 2 1 2",
                "d": "Depends on the compiler"
            },
            "correct_answer": "a"
        }
    ]
  }
  